San Diego, CA

410.980.9672 (cell) bheussler@gmail.com

# Summary

I am a full-stack software engineer who specializes in Java and modern front-end, Javascript development. For the past six years, I have worked at Life Journey, which later transitioned into Swing AI. My most recent project was Swing Index, a mobile golf app, which has 20,000 users and a 4.8 rating. On the side, I have been working on a Spring Boot and Vue.js side project, and writing about it on my personal website, builtbybrendan.com. I am looking for a new challenge that will allow me to further grow my expertise.

# Relevant Experience

**Swing Index** 

LifeJourney / Swing AI

2018 - Present

- Software Engineer
  - Designed, developed, and deployed a mobile app from the ground up, which now has 20,000 users and a 4.8 rating on the Apple App Store and Google Play Store
  - Built and maintained RESTful web services that the mobile apps use to process and persist user data
  - Lead the design and development of the Angular JS web application, which instructors use to score user submitted videos
  - Implemented an asynchronous messaging system using Apache Kafka, which was used to process user videos and other backend services, and still provide a non-blocking experience to the user
  - Integrated with the Google Play Developer API to provide subscription validation
  - Developed and modernized dozens of marketing websites, improving performance and maintainability

LifeJourney.us

LifeJourney / Swing AI

2014 - Present

- Software Engineer - Built and maintained web application in Java using Spring and Hibernate, capable of handling thousands of concurrent users by means of NGINX load balancing and multiple Tomcat servers
  - Developed and maintained frontend in AngularJS
  - Maintained 80% unit test coverage using JUnit and Jasmine on the back and front ends respectively, and built integration tests using Geb and REST Assured
  - Wrote migration scripts in Groovy that managed the migration of multiple versions of the application to satisfy multiple clients concurrently
  - Built deployment scripts in Ruby using Capistrano to deploy the application to multiple environments

## MatOnto Materials Science Framework

iNovex Information Systems 2012-2014

Software Developer

- Developed RESTful web services using Groovy on Grails that orchestrated CKAN data publishing
- Built ontologies serialized in RDF to enable federated SPARQL queries across multiple data sources
- Designed Accumulo powered Graph Data store to handle high volume integrated data

## Skills

Languages: Java (Proficient), Javascript (Proficient), Groovy (Proficient), Kotlin (Familiar), Node.js (Competent), Ruby (Competent), HTML/CSS (Proficient), Sass (Proficient), SQL (Competent)

Frameworks & Libraries: Spring (Proficient), Hibernate (Proficient), Angular JS (Proficient), React (Familiar), Vue.js (Familiar), Bootstrap (Proficient), Gulp (Proficient), Webpack (Proficient)

Certifications: Oracle Certified Associate, Java SE 7 Programmer

Volunteer: Open Source Contributor for Twitter Bootstrap, Designer and Developer of usa505.org

## Education

#### Connecticut College

New London, CT

B.A. Major Computer Science, Minor Economics (GPA 3.28)

2008 - 2012

- Relevant Courses: Computational Intelligence, Artificial Intelligence, Networks, Algorithms, Data Structures, Knowledge Representation and Reasoning, Software Engineering Methodologies